<div class="none">
<br/><br/><br/><br/>
<center><h2>CSC 204 Short Note</h2></center>
<h2>Logic and Set Theory</h2>
<p>In mathematics, a proof is a demonstration that, assuming certain axioms, some
statement is necessarily true. That is, a proof is a logical argument, not an empirical one. One must demonstrate that a proposition is true in all cases before it is
considered a theorem of mathematics. An unproven proposition for which there is
some sort of empirical evidence is known as a conjecture. Mathematical logic is
the framework upon which rigorous proofs are built. It is the study of the principles
and criteria of valid inference and demonstrations. <br/><br/>
Logicians have analyzed set theory in great details, formulating a collection of
axioms that affords a broad enough and strong enough foundation to mathematical
reasoning. The standard form of axiomatic set theory is denoted ZFC and it consists
of the Zermelo-Fraenkel (ZF) axioms combined with the axiom of choice (C). Each
of the axioms included in this theory expresses a property of sets that is widely
accepted by mathematicians. It is unfortunately true that careless use of set theory
can lead to contradictions. Avoiding such contradictions was one of the original
motivations for the axiomatization of set theory</p>
A logical conjunction is an operation on two logical propositions that produces
a value of true if both statements are true, and is false otherwise. The conjunction
(or logical AND) of P and Q, denoted by P ∧ Q. <br/> 
<p>a logical disjunction is an operator on two logical propositions that
is true if either statement is true or both are true, and is false otherwise. The disjunction (or logical OR) of P and Q.</p>
<br/>
In mathematics, a negation is an operator on the logical value of a proposition
that sends true to false and false to true. The negation (or logical NOT) of P,
denoted ¬P. <br/><br/>
The next method of combining mathematical statements is slightly more subtle
than the preceding ones. The conditional connective P → Q is a logical statement
that is read “if P then Q”.







</div>