<div class="none">
<br/>
<br/>
<br/>
<br/>
<center><h2>CHM 101 Short Note</h2></center>
    <h2>What is Chemistry, and What Can Chemistry Do for You?</h2>
    <p>
        One thing is certain: Once you start studying chemistry, all kinds of new questions will
        begin to occur to you. Let’s consider a typical day.
        Your alarm rings early, and you are groggy from sleep but eager to begin working
        on a chemistry assignment that’s coming due. Chemistry has taught you that there are
        interesting answers to questions you might once have considered silly and childish.
        Preparing tea, for example, now makes you
        wonder why the boiling water bubbles and
        produces steam while the teakettle retains its
        original shape. How do the tea leaves change
        the color of the water while the teabag remains
        as full and plump as ever? Why does sugar
        make your tea sweet, and why is the tea itself
        bitter?<br/>
        You settle down with tea and newspaper,
        and the wondering continues. An article about
        methyl bromide, a widely used pesticide, says
        some scientists think it damages the ozone
        layer. What are methyl bromide and ozone?
        How does one destroy the other, and why
        should we care? How can we know if the ozone
        really is being depleted?<br/><br/>
        Later, as you drive to the library to get some
        books you need to complete that chemistry
        assignment, you wonder why gasoline burns
        and propels your car down the road. How does it pollute the air we breathe and what does the catalytic converter do to minimize the
        pollution? At the library, you wonder why some books that are hundreds of years old
        are still in good shape while other books that are only 50 years old have pages that are
        brown, brittle, and crumbling. Can the books with damaged pages be saved?
        Chemists can answer all these questions and others like them. They are scientists
        who study the structure of material substances—collectively called matter—and the
        changes that they undergo. Matter can be solid like sugar, liquid like water, or gaseous
        like the exhaust from your car’s tailpipe. Chemistry is often defined as the study of the
        structure and behavior of matter.<br/>
        Chemists do a lot more than just answer questions. Industrial chemists are producing
        new materials to be used to build lighter and stronger airplanes, more environmentally
        friendly disposable cups, and more efficient anti‑pollution devices for your car.
        Pharmaceutical chemists are developing new drugs to fight cancer, control allergies,
        and even grow hair on bald heads.
    </p>



</div>