<div class="none">
<br/><br/><br/><br/>
<center><h2>CSC 111 Short Note</h2></center>
    <h2>Computer Hardware</h2>
    Functional units of a Computer:
        <ol>
            <li>1. Central Processing Unit (CPU)</li>
            <li>2. Main Memory</li>
            <li>3. Peripheral Units</li>
        </ol>
    <p>The hardware is divided into three areas or separate units for its operation: <br/>
        Central Processing Unit (CPU) or Processor<br/>
        Main Memory<br/>
        Peripheral Units or Electrical Gadgets <br/>
        </p><br/>

        The hardware is divided into three areas or separate units for its operation: 
        <ol>
            <li>1. Central Processing Unit (CPU)</li>
            <li>2. Main Memory</li>
            <li>3. Peripheral Units or Electrical Gadgets</li>
        </ol>
    <p>The hardware refers to the physical components or functional units of a computer which make up the computer configuration <br/>
        The design and construction of the hardware of a particular computer is referred to as its architecture or configuration <br/>
        The hardware components provide the physical interface to a computer system <br/></p><br/>
        
        
        <h3>What is hardware?</h3>
        <ol>
            <li>- A program to process words </li>
            <li>- A physical component of a computer</li>
            <li>- A database of facts</li>
            <li>- A computer programming book</li>
        </ol>
        <h3>Functional Units of a Computer</h3>
    <p>The physical parts that make up a computer consists mainly of four basic units, these parts are known as hardware, namely:
            - input unit <br/><br/>
            - storage unit, <br/><br/>
            - Central Processing Unit (CPU) or Processor  <br/><br/>
            - output unit. <br/><br/>
        </p>
        Any hardware device connected to the computer or any part of the computer outside the CPU and the working memory is known as a Peripherals <br/> 
        Central Processing unit further includes Arithmetic logic unit and control unit, as shown in the Figure
        <h3>Functional Units of a Computer</h3>
        A computer performs five major operations or functions irrespective of its size and make. <br/> These are <br/>
        <ol>
            1. it accepts data or instructions as input, <br/>
            2. it stores data and instruction <br/>
            3. it processes data as per the instructions, <br/>
            4. it controls all operations inside a computer, and <br/>
            5. it gives results in the form of output. <br/>
        </ol>
<h1>Note 2</h1>
<p>Computer science is the study of computers and computational systems. It encompasses a wide range of topics, including algorithms, programming languages, software engineering, computer architecture, and artificial intelligence.</p><br/>
<p>One of the fundamental concepts in computer science is the algorithm. An algorithm is a set of instructions that can be followed to solve a problem or perform a task. Algorithms can be simple, such as a recipe for making a cake, or complex, such as the algorithms used in machine learning.</p><br/>
<p>Programming languages are used to write algorithms and create software. Some of the most popular programming languages include C++, Java, Python, and JavaScript. Each language has its own syntax and set of features, and programmers often use multiple languages to create a project.</p><br/>
<p>Software engineering is the process of designing, developing, and maintaining software. It involves using techniques like version control, testing, and documentation to ensure that the software is reliable and easy to maintain.</p><br/>
<p>Database management is another critical area of computer science. Databases are used to store and organize large amounts of data, and are essential for many applications such as e-commerce, social media, and business intelligence. Understanding how to design and manage databases is essential for creating efficient and effective software systems.</p><br/>
<p>Artificial intelligence (AI) is another rapidly growing area of computer science. This field deals with the development of machines and software that can mimic human intelligence and thought processes. Some examples of AI include self-driving cars, voice recognition systems, and virtual personal assistants. AI has the potential to revolutionize many industries and has a wide range of applications.</p><br/>
<p>computer networks are another important area of computer science. This field deals with the communication and transfer of data between computers and other devices. It involves the use of protocols, standards, and technologies for the efficient and secure transmission of data. Understanding computer networks is essential for creating and maintaining software systems that can communicate with other systems, such as the internet.</p><br/>
<p>computer science is a vast and rapidly evolving field that encompasses a wide range of topics and technologies. It plays a critical role in modern society, and understanding its principles is essential for creating high-quality software and systems that are reliable, efficient, and easy to maintain. Whether you are a computer science student, software developer, or just interested in technology, understanding the basics of computer science is an important step in your journey.</p><br/>
</div>



