<div class="none">
<br/><br/><br/><br/>
<center><h2>CSC 111 Short Note</h2></center>
    <h2>Computer Hardware</h2>
    Functional units of a Computer:
        <ol>
            <li>1. Central Processing Unit (CPU)</li>
            <li>2. Main Memory</li>
            <li>3. Peripheral Units</li>
        </ol>
    <p>The hardware is divided into three areas or separate units for its operation: <br/>
        Central Processing Unit (CPU) or Processor<br/>
        Main Memory<br/>
        Peripheral Units or Electrical Gadgets <br/>
        </p><br/>

        The hardware is divided into three areas or separate units for its operation: 
        <ol>
            <li>1. Central Processing Unit (CPU)</li>
            <li>2. Main Memory</li>
            <li>3. Peripheral Units or Electrical Gadgets</li>
        </ol>
    <p>The hardware refers to the physical components or functional units of a computer which make up the computer configuration <br/>
        The design and construction of the hardware of a particular computer is referred to as its architecture or configuration <br/>
        The hardware components provide the physical interface to a computer system <br/></p><br/>
        
        
        <h3>What is hardware?</h3>
        <ol>
            <li>- A program to process words </li>
            <li>- A physical component of a computer</li>
            <li>- A database of facts</li>
            <li>- A computer programming book</li>
        </ol>
        <h3>Functional Units of a Computer</h3>
    <p>The physical parts that make up a computer consists mainly of four basic units, these parts are known as hardware, namely:
            - input unit <br/><br/>
            - storage unit, <br/><br/>
            - Central Processing Unit (CPU) or Processor  <br/><br/>
            - output unit. <br/><br/>
        </p>
        Any hardware device connected to the computer or any part of the computer outside the CPU and the working memory is known as a Peripherals <br/> 
        Central Processing unit further includes Arithmetic logic unit and control unit, as shown in the Figure
        <h3>Functional Units of a Computer</h3>
        A computer performs five major operations or functions irrespective of its size and make. <br/> These are <br/>
        <ol>
            1. it accepts data or instructions as input, <br/>
            2. it stores data and instruction <br/>
            3. it processes data as per the instructions, <br/>
            4. it controls all operations inside a computer, and <br/>
            5. it gives results in the form of output. <br/>
        </ol>

</div>