<div class="none">
<br/><br/><br/><br/>
<center><h2>Bio 101 Short Note</h2></center>
<h3>Evolutionary trend</h3>
    <p>Evolutionary biology is a subfield of biology concerned with the study of the evolutionary processes that produced the diversity of life on Earth.</p><br/>
    <p>Evolutionary biologists study the descent of species, and the origin of new species.<br/></p><br/>
    <p>Evolution is a scientific theory proposed by Charles Darwin. It occurs at the population level, It is made possible by genetic variations. <br/></p><br/>
    <h3>EVIDENCES THAT SPECIES EVOLVE COMES FROM THREE LINES OF  INVESTIGATION</h3>
    <p>1. Relationship were discerned among major groups of animals (Comparative anatomy)</p><br/>
    <p>2. Explorers discovered difference in the world distribution of species (Biogeography)</p><br/>
    <p>3. Geologist discovered apparent sequence of changing fossils in distinct layers of the earth</p><br/>
<h3>History of Life on Earth</h3>

    <p>- BILLIONS OF YEARS AGO EXPLOSION OF DYING STARS RIPPED THROUGH OUR GALAXY AND LEFT BEHIND A DENSE CLOUD OF DUST AND GAS
     <br/>
    - AS THE CLOUD COOLED<br/>
    - There are scientific evidence that earth and the other planets of the solar system formed about 4.6 billion years ago. <br/>
    - Evidences have shown that conditions on early Earth made the origin of life possible e.g is the fossils of microorganisms that are about  3.5 billion years old. <br/>
    - There are approximately two million species of animals and plants living today <br/>
    - How did this diversity of life come to exist? 
</p>

<p>A virus is made up of a core of genetic material, either DNA or RNA, surrounded by a protective coat called a capsid which is made up of protein. <br/>
Viruses are found in almost every ecosystem on Earth.</p><br/>
    <p>The study of viruses is known as virology.<br/>
Viruses were discovered by Dmitri Ivanovsky in 1892.</p><br/>
    <p>In its infective form, outside the cell, a virus particle is called a virion.<br/>
All viruses contain nucleic acid, either DNA or RNA (but not both), and a protein coat called Capsid, which encases the nucleic acid. Some viruses are also enclosed by an envelope of lipid and protein molecules <br/></p><br/>
    <p>Viruses depend on the host cell for almost all of their life-sustaining functions. <br/>
Existence of their life is completely dependent upon any other living cells. <br/>
Outside the living cell they remain inactive and look dead. <br/>
As soon as they enter the living cell they destroy the normal functioning and mechanism of the living cell and then starts replicating and multiply their numbers. <br/>
They does not fall under any type of cellular grade of body organisation (either unicellular or multicellular)</p><br/>
    </div>
