<div class="none">
<br/><br/><br/><br/>
<center><h2>Bio 101 Short Note</h2></center>
<h3>Evolutionary trend</h3>
    <p>Evolutionary biology is a subfield of biology concerned with the study of the evolutionary processes that produced the diversity of life on Earth.</p>
    <p>Evolutionary biologists study the descent of species, and the origin of new species.<br/></p>
    <p>Evolution is a scientific theory proposed by Charles Darwin. It occurs at the population level, It is made possible by genetic variations. <br/></p>
    <h3>EVIDENCES THAT SPECIES EVOLVE COMES FROM THREE LINES OF  INVESTIGATION</h3>
    <p>1. Relationship were discerned among major groups of animals (Comparative anatomy)</p>
    <p>2. Explorers discovered difference in the world distribution of species (Biogeography)</p>
    <p>3. Geologist discovered apparent sequence of changing fossils in distinct layers of the earth</p>
<h3>History of Life on Earth</h3>

    <p>- BILLIONS OF YEARS AGO EXPLOSION OF DYING STARS RIPPED THROUGH OUR GALAXY AND LEFT BEHIND A DENSE CLOUD OF DUST AND GAS
     <br/>
    - AS THE CLOUD COOLED<br/>
    - There are scientific evidence that earth and the other planets of the solar system formed about 4.6 billion years ago. <br/>
    - Evidences have shown that conditions on early Earth made the origin of life possible e.g is the fossils of microorganisms that are about  3.5 billion years old. <br/>
    - There are approximately two million species of animals and plants living today <br/>
    - How did this diversity of life come to exist? 
</p>

<p>A virus is made up of a core of genetic material, either DNA or RNA, surrounded by a protective coat called a capsid which is made up of protein. <br/>
Viruses are found in almost every ecosystem on Earth.</p><br/>
    <p>The study of viruses is known as virology.<br/>
Viruses were discovered by Dmitri Ivanovsky in 1892.</p><br/>
    <p>In its infective form, outside the cell, a virus particle is called a virion.<br/>
All viruses contain nucleic acid, either DNA or RNA (but not both), and a protein coat called Capsid, which encases the nucleic acid. Some viruses are also enclosed by an envelope of lipid and protein molecules <br/></p><br/>
    <p>Viruses depend on the host cell for almost all of their life-sustaining functions. <br/>
Existence of their life is completely dependent upon any other living cells. <br/>
Outside the living cell they remain inactive and look dead. <br/>
As soon as they enter the living cell they destroy the normal functioning and mechanism of the living cell and then starts replicating and multiply their numbers. <br/>
They does not fall under any type of cellular grade of body organisation (either unicellular or multicellular)</p><br/>
  <p>Biology is the study of living organisms and their interactions with each other and their environment. At its core, biology is concerned with understanding the fundamental principles that govern the behavior and functioning of living things. In this note, we will explore some of the basic principles of biology that are essential to understanding the workings of the natural world.</p><br/>
<p>One of the most fundamental principles of biology is the cell theory. This theory states that all living organisms are made up of one or more cells, which are the basic unit of life. Cells are the smallest unit of life that can perform all the functions of life, such as metabolism, growth, and reproduction. Cells are also the building blocks of larger structures, such as tissues, organs, and systems, which make up living organisms.</p><br/>
<p>Another important principle of biology is the theory of evolution. This theory states that all living organisms have evolved over time through natural selection. Evolution is the process by which certain traits become more or less common in a population of organisms over many generations. This process is driven by natural selection, which favors certain traits that help organisms survive and reproduce. Evolution is responsible for the diversity of life on Earth, from the simplest single-celled organisms to the most complex multicellular organisms.</p><br/>
<p>The theory of homeostasis is also a key principle of biology. Homeostasis refers to the ability of living organisms to maintain a relatively stable internal environment. This is important for the survival of organisms, as changes in the internal environment can have a negative impact on the functioning of cells and systems. For example, the body's internal temperature must be maintained within a narrow range in order for enzymes and other biomolecules to function properly. The maintenance of homeostasis is accomplished through various physiological mechanisms, such as the nervous and endocrine systems.</p><br/>
<p>Finally, the principle of ecology is an important part of biology. Ecology is the study of the relationships between living organisms and their environment. This includes the study of how organisms interact with each other and with their nonliving environment, including air, water, soil, and other organisms. Ecological interactions can take many forms, such as competition, predation, and symbiosis. Understanding ecology is essential for understanding the functioning of ecosystems and the impact of human activities on the natural world.
<p>In conclusion, biology is a complex and diverse field that encompasses many different areas of study. However, at its core, biology is concerned with understanding the fundamental principles that govern the behavior and functioning of living things. These principles include the cell theory, the theory of evolution, the theory of homeostasis, the concept of energy, and the principle of ecology. Understanding these principles is essential for understanding the workings of the natural world and the role of living organisms in it.</p><br/>
</p><br/>
</div>

