<div class="none">
    <br/><br/><br/><br/>
    <center><h2>MAT 111 Short Note</h2></center>
    <h3>TRIGONOMETRY</h3>
    <p>Trigonometry is a branch of mathematics that studies the relationships between the sides and angles of triangles. It is an essential tool in many fields, including engineering, physics, astronomy, and surveying. Trigonometry helps to solve problems related to angles, distances, and heights.</p>

    <p>Trigonometry is based on six trigonometric functions: sine, cosine, tangent, cosecant, secant, and cotangent. These functions are defined in terms of ratios of the sides of a right triangle. The sine function relates the ratio of the length of the opposite side to the length of the hypotenuse. The cosine function relates the ratio of the length of the adjacent side to the length of the hypotenuse. The tangent function relates the ratio of the length of the opposite side to the length of the adjacent side.</p>
    <p>Trigonometry can be used to solve a variety of problems. For example, it can be used to determine the height of a building or the distance between two points. Trigonometry can also be used to solve problems in physics, such as finding the velocity or acceleration of an object. In astronomy, trigonometry is used to calculate the position of celestial objects.</p>
    <p>Trigonometry has many practical applications. In construction, it is used to determine the angles and lengths of the beams and trusses that support buildings. In navigation, it is used to determine the direction and distance of a ship or airplane from its starting point. In surveying, it is used to measure the angles and distances between points on the Earth's surface.
</p>

    <p>Trigonometry has a long history, dating back to ancient civilizations such as the Babylonians and Greeks. The Greek mathematician Hipparchus is often credited with the development of trigonometry. Today, trigonometry is an essential part of mathematics education and is studied by students at all levels, from high school to graduate school. With its practical applications and rich history, trigonometry remains an important field of study in mathematics and beyond.

</p>


    </div>