<div class="none">
    <br/><br/><br/><br/>
    <center><h2>MAT 112 Short Note</h2></center>
    <h3>CALCULUS</h3>
    <p>Calculus is a branch of mathematics that deals with the study of rates of change and how things change over time. It has its roots in ancient Greece and has since developed into a complex and essential tool for many fields, including science, engineering, economics, and even art. Calculus is divided into two main branches: differential calculus and integral calculus.</p>
    <p>Differential calculus deals with the study of rates of change and the derivative of a function. The derivative measures how much a function changes with respect to its input variable. It is used in many areas of science and engineering, including physics, chemistry, and engineering, to calculate the rate at which things change over time. For example, the derivative of a distance function will give the velocity function, which tells us how fast an object is moving at any given time.</p>
    <p>Integral calculus deals with the study of accumulation and integration. It is the opposite of differentiation and is used to find the total amount of something over time. For example, if we know the velocity of an object over time, we can use integration to find its displacement, which tells us how far it has traveled. Integration is used in many areas of science and engineering, including physics, chemistry, and engineering, to calculate the total amount of something over time.</p>
    <p>Calculus is essential for many fields, including physics, engineering, economics, and computer science. In physics, calculus is used to model the motion of objects, calculate the rate of change of physical quantities, and analyze data from experiments. In engineering, calculus is used to design and optimize systems, analyze data, and simulate physical phenomena. In economics, calculus is used to model and optimize economic systems, predict future trends, and analyze data. In computer science, calculus is used to develop algorithms, analyze data, and optimize systems.</p>
    <p>Calculus is a fascinating and powerful tool that has revolutionized many fields. It allows us to model and understand complex systems, make accurate predictions, and optimize performance. Without calculus, many of the technological advancements we enjoy today would not have been possible. As such, it remains an essential field of study for anyone interested in science, engineering, economics, or any other field where the study of rates of change and accumulation is important.</p>

       </div>